If you're watching this video, you probably have an idea of ​​why you should actually
get health insurance
.  Previously, hospital
bills used to run into the thousands, but now they run into the
millions.
Some people have a health insurance plan
.  However, the claim doesn't
come true.  This claim process can
become very complicated.
Because they're taking
crazy plans from crazy companies
.  If you look at the market, there are
many health insurance
companies.  Every company has
different plans.  If
we look at the current market, there are a
total of more than 50 health
insurance plans.
How to choose a good plan among all these plans?
This plan has a copay.
What exactly is a Copay?  What is the room rent limit
?  What is a pre-existing disease
waiting print? There
are two types of health insurance, one is an
individual policy and the other is a family
floater health insurance policy.
Which one should you take? The main thing is
coverage, how much coverage should you take,
what kind of riders should you add?
I will explain all this pin-to-pin in this video. If
you are thinking of
taking a health insurance plan,
this video will
be very useful for you.  So watch this video
till the end and if you haven't subscribed to this channel yet,
subscribe now. I'm your Kaushik and let's
talk about how much coverage you should have first, so if we are taking a health insurance plan, how much coverage should we look for?  Many people are
blindly applying 5 to 10 locks of coverage
.  Don't do that.
Because if we look at the medical inflation rate in India, it is
12 to 15%.   This
means that our hospital bills will double in the next five years
.
For example, a surgery
was performed in the present. A
surgery was performed in the present.  It cost 2 lakhs, but
five years later the
same surgery will cost 4 lakhs.   Why is
it that if a minor
surgery is performed by mistake, how many lakhs will it cost? It used to be
thousands, now it's
all lakhs. For example, if an
appendix surgery is performed, it
will cost from 1.2 lakhs to 2.5 lakhs.  If you
undergo replacement surgery, the cost will currently range from 3.5 lakhs
to 7 lakhs.  And if we were to do a
heart stunt, it would cost 2 to 4
lakhs.  Bypass surgery
costs between 4.5 lakhs and 8 lakhs.  And if we are
in ISU for 3 to 4 days, it will cost us 2 to 5
lakhs.  There
are hospital bills like this.  If you think about it,
inflation is very high, medical
inflation, so if you ask me, it is
better to take a little more coverage. What I mean is that if you
take 40 times the amount of coverage that your entire family spends per month, it is better because of inflation. For example, if
your
entire family spends 25,000 25,000 per month, then
25,000* 40, which is 10
lakhs, take a minimum of 10 lakhs of coverage.
Similarly, if your entire family
spends 1 lakh per month, then it
is better to take 1 lakh* 40 40 lakhs of coverage.  If you
live in a metro city, it is
better to have a minimum of 15 to 20 lakhs,
so it is better to have
40 times the coverage, depending on how much you spend per month
.  And next
one, every plan you
take health insurance plan, it
has two types, one is an individual
plan and the other is a family floater plan.
Individual plan means the plan you take on yourself is
called an individual plan. For example, suppose you have taken coverage of
10 locks. If you are
admitted to the hospital for more than 24 hours in the future, only you will get
coverage.  Only you
get the claim.  For example, you
have taken an individual plan.  Your
father has been admitted to the hospital.   The
hospital spent 8 lakhs.   They won't give you
coverage if you show them your plan
.  Because you took an
individual plan.
Since it was taken on you,
coverage will only come if you are admitted.
What is a family floater plan?  For
example, you are married and
have a child. A family floater health insurance plan is for you, your wife, and your child
together
.  The three of them have the same
plan.  For example, you have 20
locks.
Suppose you have taken out 20 lock coverage and if
any of the three of you is admitted to the hospital for more than 24 hours,
this insurance company will
bear the cost.  Do you understand that coverage will be provided even if any of the three are admitted?
So what I am saying is that
who should take an individual plan and
who should take a family floater plan? If
you have a small family, you can
take a family floater in the names of your wife, daughter, and son.
Because your age is low, your father, mother,
and you are also there. Can you
take it together? If you
ask me, no. If your parents are
50, 55, or 60 years old, it is
better to take it separately in their names.  Why am I saying this? For
example, what did you do? You, your wife, your
children, and your father all
took out a combined policy, meaning you took out a 15-locks, 20-
locks coverage, let's say 15-locks
.  So later, my father underwent bypass surgery, which
cost him 15 lakhs
.  15 lakhs of coverage cost 15 lakhs
.  So, it is complete that the
entire coverage is exhausted due to the presence of one person who is older than the other
.  Later, by any chance, if your father or
mother is admitted to the hospital, there will be no coverage
because some plans work the same way. If they do, there will be no
refilling.
Some plans do have it. It is
called restoration benefit. You should also
check that. So, that means that since they are
older, if they are added to the family floater, in
most cases
they have a higher probability of being
admitted to the hospital because
due to their age, there is a chance of getting some diseases. There is a
chance of being admitted to the hospital due to asthma.
So what I am saying is that for
example, I am here. My wife and I have taken a
family floater plan together. Even if my father and
mother
take it separately, that's it. If I have added my family floater in my plan, if
they are admitted, the entire
coverage will be spent on them.
So that's why we have to face trouble later.  I took a
separate health insurance plan in their name and
my family, my
wife and I, took a family floater
health insurance plan together. Do you
understand my point that it would be better if we follow this? That's not all. You said how much
coverage should we have, whether to take an individual or a
family floater.
Earlier, they said a lot about room
rent limit, copay, etc.
We don't
know all this. We will watch your video. We will watch it till the
end. We will
learn everything. In addition, we should talk to an advisor.
That too, we should talk to an IRDAI certified
advisor and clarify all our doubts. If
you want, I will give you the link in the
comments next to the description below.
Why am I talking about this platform? I
mean, you can directly
talk to an IRDAI certified expert for free.  So, I gave it in the comments below the description of the link, and when you
click on it, it says this
.  Click here to book a free call now
.  Check out health insurance here
.  Here you
can schedule a call.
They will call you at the time you schedule.  They
don't call repeatedly.  They say they
will call you at the time you book.
Okay, so
check out the slot you like.  After checking, you will be asked to provide your
name, email ID, and phone number
.  Here you say "Brief" and
here you say "Telugu Advisor" and type
.  If you type "advisor", a
Telugu advisor will call you
.  So
tell me everything after the call.  I'm angry that I want to
get a health insurance plan, but they say
ask them everything and
they'll suggest a good plan
.  If you take it from them,
they will help you in the future, even in times of crisis.  It's
backed by Zero and has 15,000 plus
reviews.  Overall, it has a 4.9 star
rating.  So if
you want a good platform, check out the link in the description below
in the comments
.  Now, the
topic directly mentions that some plans have a
20% copay
.  For example, the copay for your
plan says 20% of the copay
.  How much did you apply for a claim in the future
?  One lakh.  If you apply for a claim of Rs 1 lakh,
the policy will cover only 80% of it
.  The remaining 20% ​​is yours to bear.
Because it says that the co-pay is 20%,
so you have to pay 20,000 out of 1 lakh rupees
from your pocket, and the company will
only pay 80,000.  So check it out. If you
ask me, most plans mention that if
your age is below 50, the cost is 0%
.  So keep in mind that if you are
over 50, you will
definitely be mentioning Planscope
.  So if it's less than 50, it's a
good idea to take it seriously.  And
what some companies are doing is that
if you are
admitted to a non-network hospital, they say that a 20% co-pay is applicable. That is, if we are
admitted to a hospital that is not tied up with that company, we have to
bear 20%. However, if we are
admitted to a network hospital, that is, a hospital that is already tied up with that insurance company, then the insurance company will bear 100%
.  And next, it's a good idea to
look at the one-room rent limit
.  Some companies are
doing some plans, which is they are setting the room rent
limit very low,
saying 2000-3000 per day
.  For example, your
company says your plan has a limit of 3000
.  You have been admitted to a high-end hospital
.  So the room rent
cost there is 6000 per day.
You thought, Sir, you would be
in the hospital for three days.  So, she mentioned that it's
6000 per day, but the policy says 3000
.  That means the insurance
company will cover 3000.  Here, they apply for the claim by saying, "
I will bear the extra 3000 for three days, which means a total of
9000, 9000 from my pocket
."  For example, let's say the bill is 10 lakhs. Let's say it's
10 lakhs for three days
.  So
what the insurance company says here is that after you apply for the claim,
we have borne 50% of the room rent limit, which is
6000, but it mentions 3000 in the policy
.  So
we will cover 50% of the room rent limit.  Here,
since we have covered 50% of the room rent limit, the overall
claim also states that we will cover 50%.  Haha,
that's the rule, yes, it means you applied for a claim for 10 lakhs,
but the insurance
company here only gives a claim of 50%, i.e. 5 lakhs
.  You will have to bear the remaining 5 lakhs
from your pocket.  The reason for that is the
low room rent limit.  So there
are many plans in the market.   There
is no room rent limit.
Even a 10,000 room is okay for them, whether it is a deluxe or a
deluxe room, do they understand that
such plans are available in the market, so
take plans that do not have any room rent limit, otherwise take plans that give a higher limit, and
do not take such plans of 3000, 2000, 4000,
so it is very important to check. The
next thing you need to check is the
waiting period. There
are three types of waiting periods in each plan. The
first one is the initial 30-day waiting
period. For example, if
you have taken this plan today,  So this
plan will not work for the first 30 days.  This means that if
we are admitted to the hospital for more than 24 hours for any reason in the first 30 days, a
claim will not be made.  If during these 30 days
you are admitted to the hospital due to an accident and
stay in the hospital for more than 24 hours, then a
claim will be made.  This means that if we are admitted to the hospital within the
first 30 days of taking out the policy for any reason other than an accident, the claim will not be received. The claim will be received
after 30 days
.  And the second one is a 24-
month waiting period for specific
surgeries, which some plans mention in advance
.  We are
giving a waiting period for these surgeries of two years.
So, due to these surgeries, we will give a claim only if you are
admitted to the hospital after two years.
So, if
you are admitted in the first two years, they will mention that you should
give a claim. For
example, cataract surgery, hernia surgery, kidney
replacement surgery, piles, sinus surgery,
tonsils, kidney stones, if you are
admitted for these reasons, they will mention that you should
give a claim for the first two years.
For these reasons, if
we are admitted in the first two years, we will not get a claim.
Remember, this is a waiting period
and the third one is a waiting period for pre-existing diseases. For example, at the
time you take the policy,
you already have diseases like BP, sugar,
thyroid, heart disease, asthma. All of these are
taken.  You should mention it on time. There will
be a waiting period for whatever you mention. For example,
your company has set a three-year plan for you
.  If you are
admitted to the hospital for those reasons within three years and
apply for a claim, the claim will not be accepted.  Remember that claims will
only be accepted after that waiting period,
and
you can only take out a
maternity plan under your maternity health insurance,
for example, if you have recently gotten
married.  So they will definitely
do family planning in the future.  A baby boy
is born.
This company will bear any costs incurred during the delivery time.
Now, if you
take a maternity plan, there will be a waiting period for that maternity plan, which is two to three
years. There are some
plans without any waiting period,
some are nine months, some are
one year, so make sure that there is a
waiting period of two to four years, and
plan accordingly.  For example,
your plan mentions a two-year waiting period
.  If the
delivery is within two years, the claim will not be received.
If the delivery is after two years, the
claim will be received only now. Keep that in mind too.
And the main thing is that
sometimes your plan will
mention something, for example, it mentioned that you should file a claim
for IVF
.  She mentioned that you did
not undergo IVF treatment and that you
cannot claim for cosmetic surgery
.  You mentioned that you didn't get it and that there are
some things that the dentist doesn't get a claim for.
You did
n't get it and that robotic
surgery is now becoming famous.  She mentioned that
she cannot claim surgery because it is done by robots
.  But
you've taken a lot of risks and the
claim won't come.  So, if you
ask me, robotic surgery
and modern cancer treatments should all be
covered.  So it is
very, very
important to check it out.  And the main thing is the claim
settlement ratio. Whatever company you
are taking a plan with, make sure that the company has a
minimum claim settlement ratio of 97%
or more. For example, there
are 98-99 in the market. If you
want, you can talk to them and
find out. If the claim
settlement ratio is 99%, tell them that. That is, if
they want, they will say the same. The
next one is the unclaimed claim ratio. This should
also be in the middle of 60-90%. If you want,
ask them.  So
only take it if it is in the middle of 60 to 90. For
example, a company has an unclaimed claim
ratio of 50%.  What that means is that
now suppose that
100 crores have come in as claims in a year. Suppose that
the
company has collected 100 crores. Out of 100 crores,
only 50 crores have been claimed. Suppose that it has taken 100 crores and given
only 50 crores to everyone. The
incurred claim ratio of that company is 50%, which means that the
company concentrates more on profits than on
giving claims. Suppose that
a company has an incurred claim ratio of 80%.
Now if it has collected 100 crores, it has given
80 crores in the form of premium from the people.
Which is good, it should be like that. Suppose it has
taken 100 and
given 100. The company still has to run,
so at any time, make sure that the incurred claim ratio is 60
to 90%. And the main thing is that there should be
more network hospitals for  For example, suppose you
are in Hyderabad and are taking treatment at a certain company.
So, check how many
network hospitals there are. There should
definitely be a lot of them.
If there are fewer, you will have to submit all the bills again
.  First you have to pay all the bills
from your pocket and then
submit all the bills to the insurance company and they will check and give you the money.
This is why there are
more network hospitals. Suppose you have joined directly. They say that they will
take care of them. And complaints.
Complaints should be less. Look at
how many complaints
are coming for every 10,000 clients. If you want to take it from a company,
ask them how many complaints there are. They will tell you that it is
very important to check everything and take a good plan. If you want, I will
talk to you once. If you think it is better, it is
free. So talk to them. They will
suggest. If you want, you can
take it from them. Otherwise, take it outside. It is
free. At the end of the day, what we
need is a good suggestion. Now, what I
have said is what they will say in this video.
But it is
very good to verify it once again. You can
take it offline, take it online,
take it from any platform you like.  It's okay, it's
better to take it at the end of the day. Do you
understand? If you liked this information,
tell me if you liked it, or if you didn't like it,
tell me if you didn't like it.
If you want to talk to Dettol for free, check the link in the description below in the
comments.
Thank you so much for watching.
Jai Hind
Boss Wala Be the Boss.